Xavier Vilà Albiol

Front-end Developer

Xavier Vilà Albiol

1610 Camden St. Ferndale, MI, 48220

+1 313-952-6573

xavi.vila.albiol@gmail.com

Summary

Versatile Front-end Developer with lots of experience in **HTML** and **CSS** implementation, Cross-browser and Responsive design. Wide range of professional experience in **javascript** using several frameworks, libraries and vanilla js. Experience in agile working environments and Scrum methodology.

Skills

- HTMI
- CSS / Sass
- Javascript

- React
- Redux
- Jest

- Node
- Express
- npm

- npm/yarn
- webpack
- Agile

Experience

Best Doctors Technologies / Senior Front-end developer SEPTEMBER 2012 - APRIL 2017, PALMA DE MALLORCA (SPAIN)

• Refactoring the javascript of the Platform.

- Creation and maintenance of the CSS of the Platform based on OOCSS, developed using SASS.
- Task automation using Gulp.
- Implementation of the web app using Node, Express and AngularJS.
- Analysis and creation of task using Scrum and Agile methodology

Can Antaviana / Front-end developer

FEBRUARY 2011 - SEPTEMBER 2012, LES BORGES BLANQUES (SPAIN)

 Creation and maintenance of the HTML, CSS and javascript in several projects. Implementation of the CMS of the company

Freelance / Front-end and Back-end developer

JULY 2009 - SEPTEMBER 2012, REMOTE
Design and implementation of different projects such as el portal dels pirineus or isistemes

Hospital Santa Maria / IT department

JULY 2007 - JULY 2009, LLEIDA (SPAIN)

Web maintenance...

Red Cross / Graphic Design and Website Development

MAY 2006 - JUNE 2007, LLEIDA (SPAIN)

Graphic design and web maintenance.

Education

Bachelor's Degree, Digital Communications and Multimedia / Universitat Oberta de Catalunya (UOC) - Barcelona (Spain)

SEPTEMBER 2009 - DECEMBER 2015.

Projects

Personal Github Repository

APRIL 2017 - PRESENT

https://github.com/txiverke